[
    {
        "question": "What does SQL stand for?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "Structured Query Language",
        "choices": [
            "Structured Query Language",
            "Sequential Query Language",
            "Syntax Query Language",
            "System Query Language"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "When was SQL commercially available?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "1979",
        "choices": [
            "1979",
            "1995",
            "1970",
            "1985"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which database type uses SQL?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "Relational databases",
        "choices": [
            "Cloud databases",
            "Time series databases",
            "Relational databases",
            "NoSQL databses"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which database is an example of a NoSQL database?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "CouchDB",
        "choices": [
            "Microsoft SQL Server",
            "Druid",
            "Oracle Autonomous Database",
            "CouchDB"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What statement is used in SQL to delete existing records within a table?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "DELETE statement",
        "choices": [
            "SELECT statement",
            "UPDATE statement",
            "INSERT statement",
            "DELETE statement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which SQL command is used to create an entirely new database?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "CREATE DATABASE statement",
        "choices": [
            "CREATE DATABASE statement",
            "DELETE TABLE statement",
            "UPDATE DATABASE statement",
            "INSERT TABLE statement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of SQL command is used to control access to data within a database?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "DCL (data control language) command",
        "choices": [
            "DCL (data control language) command",
            "DML (data manipulation language) command",
            "DDL (data definition language) command",
            "DQL (data query language) command"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of databases tend to be horizontally scalable?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "NoSQL databases",
        "choices": [
            "Stream databases",
            "NoSQL databases",
            "Cloud databases",
            "SQL databases"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is SQL commonly used for?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "Data storage and data processing on websites and applications",
        "choices": [
            "Analyzing and visualizing big data",
            "Analyzing market environments for business decisions",
            "Building computer systems software",
            "Data storage and data processing on websites and applications"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which career path may benefit from SQL knowledge?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "Data scientist",
        "choices": [
            "Business analyst",
            "Data scientist",
            "Software engineer",
            "SEO analyst"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the best way to retain SQL commands?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "Practicing and using SQL in a database management system",
        "choices": [
            "Taking online courses and video tutorials",
            "Attending SQL certification programs",
            "Installing multiple SQL database management systems",
            "Practicing and using SQL in a database management system"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tool is used to write and interact with SQL?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "'Microsoft\u2019s SQL Server Management Studio'",
        "choices": [
            "'Oracle\u2019s SQL developer'",
            "'DataGrip'",
            "'Microsoft\u2019s SQL Server Management Studio'",
            "'SQL Workbench'"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a common difference between SQL and NoSQL databases?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "SQL databases are table-based, while NoSQL databases can be graph-based, document-based or wide column stores",
        "choices": [
            "NoSQL databases are best suited for multi-row transactions",
            "'SQL databases tend to be easier for developers than NoSQL databases",
            "SQL databases are table-based, while NoSQL databases can be graph-based, document-based or wide column stores",
            "SQL databases are more often horizontally scalable than NoSQL databases."
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which companies or platforms use SQL?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "Facebook, Spotify, Revolut, Twitter, Instagram",
        "choices": [
            "Microsoft, Oracle, Druid, CloudDB",
            "Facebook, Spotify, Revolut, Twitter, Instagram",
            "IBM, CouchDB, DataGrip",
            "MySQL, SQLfiddle, Toad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the difficulty level in learning and using SQL?",
        "category": "SQL Programming",
        "answer": "Hard",
        "choices": [
            "Hard",
            "Advanced",
            "Intermediate",
            "Easy"
        ]
    }
]